<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Several acts and laws passed by the great and general court or assembly of Their Majesties province of Massachusetts-Bay in New England. Convened and held at Boston, the eighth day of June. 1692. Anno Regni Gulielmi, et Mariæ, Regis et Reginæ Angliæ, Scotiæ, Franciæ, et Hiberniæ, quarto</title>
            <title>Public General Acts. 1692.</title>
            <author>Massachusetts. Council.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1692</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 41 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 10 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A50071</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing M1016</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R217665</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99829320</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99829320</idno>
            <idno type="VID">33757</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A50071)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 33757)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1918:4,)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Several acts and laws passed by the great and general court or assembly of Their Majesties province of Massachusetts-Bay in New England. Convened and held at Boston, the eighth day of June. 1692. Anno Regni Gulielmi, et Mariæ, Regis et Reginæ Angliæ, Scotiæ, Franciæ, et Hiberniæ, quarto</title>
                  <title>Public General Acts. 1692.</title>
                  <author>Massachusetts. Council.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 16 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>printed by Benjamin Harris, printer to His Excellency, the Governour and Council,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Boston :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1692.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Pages have print show-through, with slight loss of text.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  William and Mary, 1689-1702 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-03</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-04</date>
            <label>Pip Willcox</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-04</date>
            <label>Pip Willcox</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:33757:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>Several ACTS AND LAWS Paſſed by the Great and General Court or Aſſembly of Their
Majeſties Province of the Maſſachuſetts-Bay, in NEW ENGLAND.</p>
            <p>Convened and Held at <hi>Boston,</hi> the Eighth Day of <hi>June.</hi> 1692 <hi>Anno Regni
Gulielmi, et Mariae, Regis et Reginae Angliae, Scotiae, Franciae, et Hiberniae, Quarto</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>BOSTON,</hi> Printed by <hi>Benjamin Harris,</hi> Printer to His Excellency, the Governour
and Council. 1692.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="Acts">
            <div n="local laws" type="Act">
               <pb facs="tcp:33757:2"/>
               <pb n="1" facs="tcp:33757:2"/>
               <opener>
                  <dateline>Province of the MASSACH<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>SETS-BAY.</dateline>
               </opener>
               <head>An Act, For Continuing the Local Laws, to Stand in Force, till November the 10th.
1692.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>BE it Ordered and Enacted,</hi> By the Governour, Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cil and Repreſentatives Convened in
General Aſſembly, and it is hereby, <hi>Ordered and Enacted,</hi> By the Autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity of the
Same, That all the Local Laws Reſpectively Ordered and Made by the Late Governour, and Company of
the <hi>Maſſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chuſets-Bay,</hi> and the Late Government of <hi>New Plymouth,</hi> being not
Repugnant to the <hi>Laws of England,</hi> nor Incon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiſtent with the Preſent Conſtitution
and Settlemtent by Their <hi>Majeſties Royal Charter,</hi> Do Remain and Continue in <hi>Full
Force</hi> in the Reſpective Places, for which they were Made and Uſed, until the Tenth Day of
<hi>November</hi> Next; Except in Caſes where other Proviſion is or ſhall be made by this
Court, or Aſſembly.</p>
               <p>And all Perſons are Required to conform themſelves accordingly; And the ſeveral Juſtices
are hereby Impowred to the Execution of Said Laws as the Magiſtrates formerly were.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="tax arrears" type="Act">
               <opener>
                  <dateline>Province of the Maſſachuſetts-Bay,</dateline>
               </opener>
               <head>An Act For Enforcing the Collecting and Paying in the Arrears of Publick Aſſeſsments,
&amp;c.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>WHereas</hi> by the Late Governments within the Colonies of the <hi>Maſſachuſets</hi>
and <hi>New-Plimouth,</hi> now by Their Majeſties ROYAL CHARTER United and Incorporated, Several
Publick Taxes and Aſſeſsments have reſpectively been granted for the Security and Defence
of Their Majeſties Subjects and Intereſts, and the Defraying of the Publick Charges ariſing
by the War, with Their Majeſties E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nemies, <hi>French</hi> and <hi>Indians,</hi> ſince the
Firſt Day of <hi>October,</hi> ONE THOUSAND SIX HUNDRED EIGHTY NINE. And have been
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:33757:3"/>committed unto the Conſtables or other Perſons appointed Collectors with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in
the Reſpective Towns and Villages, to Collect and Gather in, the Time pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fixed for paying in of
the ſame unto the Treaſurers or Receivers reſpectively ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed in the ſaid Colonies
being ſome time ſince paſt, and a conſiderable part of every of the ſaid
Aſſeſsments being behind Uncollected, of at leaſt not paid in unto the ſaid Treaſurers
or Receivers, and the Country being Indebted unto ſeveral particular Perſons for Service done,
And others who have advanced Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neys for carrying on and defraying of the Charges ariſing by the
War, upon the Credit of ſaid Aſſeſsments.—</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>BE if therefore Ordered and Enacted</hi> By the Governour, Council, and Repreſentatives
Convened in General Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſembly; And it is hereby <hi>Ordered and Enacted</hi> By the Autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity
of the ſame, That all and every Conſtable and Conſtables or other Collect<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ors within the
Reſpective Towns and Villages within this Province, who at any time ſince the ſaid firſt
day of <hi>October,</hi> One Thouſand Six Hundred Eighty Nine have had any of the Publick
Aſſeſsments granted as aforeſaid committed unto them, or any of them to Collect and Pay in
as aforeſaid, who have not perfected their ſaid Collections, and adjuſted and iſſued
their Accounts thereof with the Reſpective Treaſurers as by Order of Court, or Warrant they are
Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rected, Be and are hereby fully Authorized and Impowred, to Collect, and Ga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther in the
Arrearges of all ſuch Publick Taxes and Aſſeſsments, And to do and Execute therein all and
whatſoever ſhall or may be needful for the Effectual Pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſuing of the Same, as by Order or
Warrant they might at any time heretofore have Lawfully done by ſuch Rules, Methods and
Directions of Law, as have lately been uſed, and in Force; The Diſmiſſing of any ſuch
Perſon or Perſons, from his or their Office, of Conſtable or any alteration of the Goverment,
ſince made notwithſtanding. And all and every ſuch Conſtables or Collectors, are
like<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe Enjoyned and Required to Make up, Settle, and Adjuſt their Accompts, &amp; Payments,
of all Publick Aſſeſsments committed unto them, as aforeſaid with the Reſpective
Treaſurers, or Receivers, as <hi>Per</hi> Order or Warrant, they are Directed on or before the
firſt Day of <hi>November</hi> next, after the Date hereof. And in caſe any Conſtable, or
Collector, ſhall Neglect, and Fail of performing his Duty, in this behalf. That then the Sheriff
of the County by Warrant from the Trea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſurer, ſhall Levy all ſuch Arrears, by Diſtreſs,
&amp; Sale of Goods of ſuch defective Conſtable or Collector. Returning the Overplus (if any
be,) And if no Goods can be found, then to take the Body of ſuch Conſtable or Collector, and
Commit him to Priſon. And all ſuch Conſtables or Collectors where the Defect doth not happen,
through their own Default, ſhall be Relieved by the Town, and the Select men are to make due
proviſion for the ſame.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="collecting arrears" type="Act">
               <pb n="3" facs="tcp:33757:3"/>
               <opener>
                  <dateline>Province of the MASSACH<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>SETS-BAY.</dateline>
               </opener>
               <head>An Act, For Collecting the Arrears, of Town and Country Rates.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>WHereas</hi> ſeveral Taxes or Aſſeſsments, neceſſary for the Support of the
Miniſty, and other Publick Charges, ariſing in the ſeveral Counties, and Towns, within this
Province, have been laid upon the Inhabitants, and Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derly committed to the Conſtables or
Collectors, by the Select men, or Aſſeſſors, in the ſeveral Towns, ſince the firſt
Day of <hi>May,</hi> in the Year, One Thouſand Six Hundred Eighty and Nine, and in many places
remains uncollected, and unpaid; in whole, or in part.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Be it therefore Ordered, and Enacted,</hi> By His Excellency, the Governour, Council, and
Repreſentatives, in Ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neral Aſſembly, and by the Authority of the ſame, it is
<hi>Enacted,</hi> That all ſuch Conſtables and Collectors, be Authorized, and Required, and are
hereby Authorized, and Required to Collect all ſuch Rates, or Aſſeſſments ſo committed
to him, or them, that remain yet Uncollected, and to pay the ſame unto the County Treaſurer in
each County Reſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctively, or Select Men in being in each Town Reſpectively where they were
made, and to be improved to the uſe, or uſes, for the which they were granted, and to finiſh
their Accompts with them, at or before the Tenth Day of <hi>December</hi> next enſuing, on
Penalty of Forty Shillings <hi>Per</hi> Month, for every Month's default after the ſaid Tenth Day
of <hi>December,</hi> to be recovered by the County Treaſurer, or Select Men Reſpectively of
any ſuch Defective Conſtables or Collectors, at any Court of Pleas in the ſame county. And
where any Conſtables or Collectors are Dead, or Removed, and the Aſſeſſments committed to
them, remain Uncollected, or any part thereof; the Select Men are Impowred &amp; Required, to
depute meet perſons to Collect the ſame, and the perſons ſo deputed are required to Collect
what ſo remains, and to pay the ſame accordingly.</p>
               <p>And it is further ORDERED, that in any County. Town or Towns, where ſuch Tax or Taxes, have
been agreed on ſince the ſaid firſt Day of <hi>May,</hi> and not Aſſeſſed upon the
Inhabitants, the Select Men of the ſeveral Towns, are <hi>hereby Required forthwith</hi> to make
ſuch Rates <hi>or</hi> Aſſeſſments, and commit them with <hi>Warrant to their
Constables,</hi> on the like Penalty, of Forty Shillings Money <hi>for</hi> every Month's defect,
and to cauſe them to be collected accompted <hi>for</hi> and paid as <hi>aforeſaid.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="granting assessment" type="Act">
               <pb n="4" facs="tcp:33757:4"/>
               <opener>
                  <dateline>Province of the <hi>Maſſachuſetts-Bay.</hi>
                  </dateline>
               </opener>
               <head>An Act, For the Granting to Their Majeſties an Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeſsment upon Polls and
Eſtates.</head>
               <p>WE Their Majeſties Loyal and Dutiful Subjects, the Repreſenta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tives of Their Majeſties
Province of the Maſſachuſets-Bay in <hi>New-England,</hi> Convened in General Aſſembly,
being ſenſible of the Neceſſity of Raiſing Moneys for the Defence of Their Majeſties
Subject, and Intereſts, and Proſecution of the War againſt their <hi>French</hi> and
<hi>Indian</hi> Enemies, and for the Defraying of other the Publick Char<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ges of the Province. Do
Unammouſly and Chearfully grant unto Their Moſt Excellent Majeſties, their Heirs and
Succeſſors, to the End and Intents afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, a Rate or fax to be Aſſeſſed upon the
Free-holders, Inhabitants, and other Their Majeſties Subjects, Reſident within the ſaid
Province, in manner as is here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>after after <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap>; be
paid in Mony, or to the Satisfaction of the Treaſurer</p>
               <p>And Pray that it may be <hi>Enacted,</hi> And be it accordingly <hi>Enact<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed</hi> By the
Governour, Council and Repreſentatives, Convened in General Aſſembly. And it is <hi>Enacted
and Ordained</hi> by the Autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity of the ſame. That the Treaſurer do forthwith ſend forth
his War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rants to the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> Men of each Town within this
Province, requiring the ſaid Select Men, to Cauſe the Inhabitants of ſuch Town to meet
together ſome time in the Month of <hi>July</hi> next; who being ſo Aſſembled, are Required
to Chooſe one of their Free-holders to be a Commiſſioner for ſaid Town, which
Commiſſioner together with the Select-Men within the Month of <hi>August</hi> fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowing,
ſhall make a true Liſt of all the Male Perſons in the ſaid Town, from ſixteen Years Old
and Upwards; and a true Eſtimation of the Juſt Yearly Vaine and Income, ſo near as they can
by all lawful means, which they may uſe, of all Eſtates Real and Perſonal being, or reputed
to be the Eſtate of all and every the Perſons in the ſame Town, or under their Cuſtody or
Manage<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment. All which Perſons and Eſtates, are by the ſaid Commiſſioner and Select-Men
to be Taxed and Aſſeſſed as followeth, <hi>viz.</hi> Every Perſon aforeſaid at Ten
Shillings by the Poll (except the Members of the Council, Settled Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſters, and Grammar
School-Maſters, and others Devoted to the Miniſtry, and Students or the Colledge) and all
Houſes, Lands, Stock, Goods and Merchan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dizes and Eſtates whatever, Real and Perſonal at a
quarter part of one years Value or Income thereof. All perſons who through Age or Infirmity, are
un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able to manage their Affairs, are to be free of the Poll-Tax; at the diſcretion of the
Select-Men.</p>
               <p>And it is further <hi>Enacted,</hi> That the Commiſſioner of each Town, upon the Firſt
<hi>Wedneſday</hi> of <hi>September</hi> next, ſhall carry the Liſts of ſaid Town, unto the
Shire Town, within the ſame County, where the Commiſſioners of
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:33757:4"/>the ſeveral, Towns ſhall meet together to Peruſe, Examine, Correct and
Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fect the ſaid Liſts; which Liſts ſo Examined, Perfected and Signed by the ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jor part
of the ſaid Commiſſioners ſo met, ſhall by one of the ſaid Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners, whom the
reſt ſhall appoint thereto, be forthwith Tranſmitted unto the Treaſurer, with upon the
Receipe thereof, ſhall Iſſue forth his Warrants to the Conſtables of the Reſpective
Towns, to Collect the Sum Total of each Liſt upon the Inhabitant of ſuch Towns, according to
their reſpective proportion: And in caſe any perſon or perſons ſhall neglect, or refuſe
to make payment of the Sum or Sums ſo Aſſeſſed upon them; then to Levy the ſame by
<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> and Sale of Goods of ſuch perſon or perſons
ſo neglecting of refuſing; returning the Over-plus, if any be. And the Conſtables are to pay
in unto the Treaſurer the one half of the ſaid Tax, at or before the Twenty Fifth of
<hi>December</hi> next, and the other Half at or before the Firſt Day of <hi>May</hi> following,
and make up their Accompts with the ſaid Preaſurer by the firſt of <hi>June</hi> next, on
pain of Forfeiting Ten Pounds in Mony unto Their Majeſties, for the Sup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>port of the Government.
As alſo to pay all Arrears of Said Aſſeſſments, The Said TEN POUND Forfeiture: And
Arrears to be Sued for, and Reco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vered by the Treaſurer, in the Inferiour Court of Pleas, in the
County where ſuch Conſtable lives, by Bill, Plaint, Action or Information.</p>
               <p>Provided alſo, that where Perſons, who are not Settled Inhabitants, and their Eſtates
being Rated, yet are removed and gone before the ſame can be Collect<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, it ſhall be abated to
the Conſtable that was to Collect the ſame. Certifi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cate thereof being given by the
Select-Men.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>And it is further Enacted by the Authority</hi> aforeſaid, That this Act for the granting
to Their Majeſties an Aſſeſsment upon Polls and Eſtates, ſhall continue in Force only
for this preſent Levy, and no longer. Any thing to the contrary notwithſtanding.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="shipping impost" type="Act">
               <opener>
                  <dateline>Province of the MASSACH<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>SETS-BAY.</dateline>
               </opener>
               <head>An Act, For Impoſt, Exciſe, and Tonnage of Ship<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ping.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>WE Their Majesties most Loyal, and Dutiful Subjects, the Repreſentatives, of this their
Majeſties Province, Conve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned in General Aſſembly, being duely ſenſible of the great
Charges and Expences, which have already ariſen, and must neceſſarily be Daily Growing and
Increaſing, in Defending and Securing, of Their Majesties Subjects and Intereſts, and in the
Proſecuting of the War, againſt their French and Indian Enemies: have Chearfully and
<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nanimouſly Given and Granted, and do hereby Give and
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:33757:5"/>Grant unto their moſt Excellent Majeſties, Their Heirs and Succeſſours,
to the End and Intent aforeſaid; and for the Defraying of other the necceſſary and Contingent
Charges, in and about the Support of the Government of this their Majesties Province, the ſeveral
Duties Impost and Exciſe on the Wines, Liquours and Goods hereafter mentioned. And humbly
beſeech their Majeſties to accept the ſame.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <hi>And that it may be Enacted, and be it Enacted,</hi> By the Governour, Council and
Repreſentatives in General Court Aſſembled. <hi>And it is hereby Enacted, and Ordai<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned, By
the Authority of the Same,</hi> That from and after the twenty ninth. Day of this Inſtant
<hi>June,</hi> In the Year of Our Lord, One Thouſand Six Hundred Ninety and Two there ſhall be
paid by the Importer, for all <hi>Wines or Liquours,</hi> and <hi>Goods</hi> hereafter ſpecifyed
that ſhall be Imported into this Province, the Rates hereafter mentioned.</p>
               <p>That is to ſay, for every <hi>Pipe of common Fyall Wine th ſumme of one Pound,</hi> Every
<hi>Pipe of Paſſada wine, one Pound Fifteen Shillings,</hi> Every <hi>Pipe of Madera Wine, one
Pound Ten Shillings,</hi> Every <hi>Pipe of Canary, Mallage, &amp; Sherry Wines, Two Pounds</hi>
Every <hi>Pipe of Port Wine, one Pound Five Shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings,</hi> and ſo Proportionably for greater or
leſſer quantities, and for every <hi>Gallen of Rum</hi> or other <hi>Spirits</hi> Imported as
aforeſaid, Six pence. All which Impoſts as aforeſaid, ſhall be paid in Currant Money of
this Province, the one half at or before the Landing thereof, the other half to be allowed three
Month's for payment, Provided there be Bond and Security given to the Commiſſioners ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed
by this Act, or ſuch as they ſhall appoint, for the payment thereof at time as aforeſaid.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>And it is further Enacted by the Authority</hi> aforeſaid, That every Merchant or other
Perſon Importing any Wines or other Liquors into this Province, ſhall be allowed Twelve <hi>per
Cent</hi> for Leakage: Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vided ſaid Wines have not been filled up Aboard. And that every
Hogſhead of Wine or other Liquors that ſhall not have full ſeven Inches left therein, and
e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very Butt or Pipe of Wine, or other Liquors that hath not nine Inche; left therein ſhall be
accomred for Outs, and the Merchant or Importer to pay no Impoſt or Duty for the ſame.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>And it is hereby further Enacted and Decla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red by the Authority aforeſaid.</hi> That if
all or any Wines or Liquors as aforeſaid be Landed, and afterwards be Exported out of the
Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vince within Nine Months after Importation thereof, there ſhall be Repayed or Diſcounted by
ſaid Commiſſioners, or their Order, unto the Importers or their Aſſigns, two third parts
of what they Paid or Secured to be paid, for ſo much as they Export; he or they making Oath, That
it is the ſame Wines, or Liquors, for which the whole Duty had been duly paid or ſecured to be
paid: And that its Exported within the time limited as aforeſaid by this Act.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>And it is alſo Enacted</hi> by the Authority aforeſaid, That for all Goods, Wares and
Merchandizes that ſhall be Imported to any part of this Province, after the twenty ninth day of
this Inſtant <hi>June</hi> (<hi>Sale, Cotton-Wool, Proviſions,</hi> and every other thing of
the growth and product of <hi>New-En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gland</hi>
                  <pb n="7" facs="tcp:33757:5"/>only Excepted) there ſhall be paid by the Importer, the ſeveral Impoſts and
Duties following, That is to ſay, For every Hundred Pound Sterling in <hi>Engliſh</hi>
Merchandizes, at the prime coſt in <hi>England</hi> (the Invoices thereof to be produced and
ſhown) the ſum of Ten Shillings.</p>
               <list>
                  <item>For every Hogſhead of Sugar, one ſhilling.</item>
                  <item>For every Hogſhead of Molaſſes, ſix-pence.</item>
                  <item>For every Hogſhead of Tobacco, ſix-pence.</item>
                  <item>For every Ton of Logg-wood, one ſhilling.</item>
               </list>
               <p>And for all other Commodities, Goods, Wares, and Merchandizes (except as before excepted) One
Penny for every Twenty Shillings value here. All Entries where the Impoſt or Duty to be paid,
doth not exceed Four Shillings, to be made without Charge to the Importer. And not more than
ſix-pence to be paid for any other ſingle Entry to what value ſoever.</p>
               <p>And the better to prevent Fraud, <hi>It is further Enacted.</hi> By the Authority aforeſaid,
That all Merchants, Factors, or other Perſon or Perſons, Importers, being Owners of, or having
any of the Wines, Liquors, Goods, Wares, and Merchandizes Conſigned to them, that by this Act are
liable to pay Impoſt or Duty. Such Perſon or Perſons ſhall by themſelves, or, order,
cauſe the ſame to be Entred with ſaid Commiſſioners or ſuch as they ſhall ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>point;
and pay their Duty, or ſecure the ſame to be paid, as by this ACT is provided, before ſuch
Wines, Liquors, Goods, or Merchandize be Landed or Put into any Boat or Veſſel, in order to be
Landed, on the Forfeiture of ſuch Wines, Liquors, Goods, Wares, and Merchandize, ſo Landed, or
Put into any Boat or Veſſel, in order to be Landed: One third part to Their Majeſties, one
third part to the Governour, one third part to the Informer, that ſhall Sue for the ſame, by
Bill, Plaint or Information, in any Court of Record within this Province: Any thing in this Act, or
any other to the contrary not<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>withſtanding.</p>
               <p>And all manner of Perſons, are hereby required, to be aiding, and aſſiſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the ſaid
Commiſſioners, their Agents, the Informer, Diſcoverer or Seizor of ſuch Wines, Liquors or
Goods ſo Landed or Unloaden contrary to the true Intent and Meaning of this Act.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>And it is further Enacted,</hi> That it ſhall and may be lawful for ſuch as are Impowred
or Improved by the Commiſſioners, or for the Informer or Diſcoverer, by Warrant from the
Lievtenant Governour, or any Juſtice of the Peace, within this Province, (to that purpoſe
firſt obtain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed) with one Conſtable or more, to Search according to Law, all manner of
Houſes, Cellars, &amp; Ware-houſes, for ſuch Wines &amp; Liquors, as they, or any of them
ſhall be informed were carried there to be Concealed, in prejudice to the true meaning of this
Act, and with Intent to defraud Their Majeſties of their ſaid Duties. And ſuch Wines and
Liquors ſo found, ſhall be forfeited and condemned in manner and form before mentioned. Always
provided
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:33757:6"/>that ſuch Search be made in the day time, and within the ſpace of one month
after the Offence ſuppoſed to be committed.</p>
               <p>Provided alſo, That if the Information, whereupon any Houſe ſhall come to be Searched,
ſhall prove to be falſe, That then, and in ſuch caſe, the Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty injured ſhall recover
his full Damages and Coſts againſt the Informer, by Action of Treſpaſs to be therefore
brought againſt ſuch Informer:</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>And it is further Enacted and Ordained,</hi> By the Authority aforeſaid. That there
ſhall be given and granted, and paid unto Their Majeſties, their Heirs and Succeſſors for
the Uſes aforeſaid. An Exciſe upon all <hi>Wines, Brandy, Rhum,</hi> and other Diſtilled
Liquors, <hi>Perry, Beer, Ale, Cyder</hi> and <hi>Methiglin,</hi> that ſhall be Sold by Retail in
any Town or Place within this Province, by thoſe that ſhall Retail the ſame, in manner and
form as is herereafter Expreſſed and Declared: That is to ſay,
<list>
                     <item>For every Gallon of common Fyal-wine, the Sum of Six-pence.</item>
                     <item>Every Gallon of Paſſado, Malago, Canary, and Sherry, the ſum of Twelve-pence.</item>
                     <item>Every Gallon of Madera, the ſum of Eight-pence.</item>
                     <item>Every gallon of Rhum, and all other ſorts of Diſtilled Spirits, the ſum of One
Shilling.</item>
                     <item>Every Barril of Perry, Beer, Ale, and Cy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der, the ſum of One Shilling and
ſix-pence.</item>
                     <item>And every gallon of Metheglin, the ſum of Four-pence.</item>
                  </list>
               </p>
               <p>All Currant Money of this Province, and after that Rate, for any greater or leſſer
Quantities.</p>
               <p>And for the due and orderly Collecting and Receiving of the Exciſe aforeſaid.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>It is hereby further Enacted and Declared by the Authority aforeſaid,</hi> That all
Retailers of <hi>Wine, Brandy, Rhum,</hi> and other Diſtilled Liquors, <hi>Perry, Beer, Ale,
Cyder</hi>
                  <pb n="9" facs="tcp:33757:6"/>and <hi>Metheglin</hi> within this Province, having any of the ſaid Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quors in
their Reſpective Houſes, or elſe-where belonging unto them; at the time of the Publiſhing
of this Act, ſhall make due Entry, and pay the Duties and Exciſe aforeſaid, for the ſame as
is herein before-mentioned. And upon their further Receipt or Pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chaſe of all, or any of the
Liquors before-mentioned, ſhall within twenty four Hours after the Receipt or Purchaſe thereof,
make Entry with the ſaid Commiſſioners or ſuch Perſon or Perſons that ſhall be
appointed to Receive and Collect the ſame, and pay the Duties and Exciſe aforeſaid, under the
penalty of Forfeiture of all ſuch Liquors as ſhall be found in any Retailers Houſe, not being
duely Entred, and the Exciſe paid as aforeſaid, and every Retailer who ſhall make his own
Cyder, and Metheglin, Brew his own Beer, or Ale, or Diſtill ſtrong Liquors, ſhall from time
to time, and at all times, when he or they ſhall make, brew, or diſtill the ſame, make Entry
with ſaid Commiſſioners, or ſuch other Perſon or Perſons as for that purpoſe ſhall
be appointed, of all ſuch Cyder, Metheglin, Ale, Beer, or Diſtilled Liquors, by them made,
brewed or diſtilled, and pay the Exciſe as aforeſaid, under the like penalty and forfeiture
of all ſuch Liquors as ſhall be found in any Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tailers Houſe not Entred, and the Exciſe
thereof not paid in man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner before Expreſſed, and to that end, it ſhall and may be law<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful to
and for ſuch <hi>Officer</hi> or <hi>Officers</hi> as by the <hi>Commiſſioners</hi> ſhall
be <hi>Appointed</hi> and <hi>Impowred,</hi> when, and ſo often; as he or they ſhall think fit,
in the day time, to <hi>Enter</hi> into any <hi>Retailers</hi> Houſe, <hi>Cellar or
Ware-houſe</hi> to <hi>Search for</hi> ſuch Wines <hi>or Liquors,</hi> &amp;c. as <hi>are</hi>
not duely <hi>Entred,</hi> nor the Exciſe paid <hi>for</hi> the ſame, and ſuch Wines <hi>or
Liquors,</hi> &amp;c. ſo found, to <hi>Seiz</hi> and <hi>Secure</hi> in <hi>order</hi> to the
<hi>Tryal,</hi> &amp; Conviction thereof, &amp; to gage any Cask or Casks for that end &amp;
purpoſe. <hi>Provided always, That it ſhall and may be lawful to and for the Commiſſioners
to agree with any Retailer for his Exciſe, for one whole year, in one intire Sum to be paid
quarterly, as they in their diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cretion ſhall think fit to agree for, without making any Entry
as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <hi>And it is further Enacted by the Authority <hi>aforeſaid That no Perſon or Perſons, on
any pretence or colour whatſoe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver for the future, ſhall or may take in, receive, harbour,
entertain, keep or conceal, in his or their Dwelling-Houſes, Cellars, or Ware-houſes, any
quantity or Parcel of Wines or other Liquors, belonging to any Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cenſed Perſon or Perſons;
Retailer or Retailers, under the penalty of forfeiture of Twenty Pounds for every ſuch Quantity
or Parcel of Wines or other Liquors ſo taken or received, harboured, entertained, kept and
concealed as aforeſaid.</hi>
                  </hi>
               </p>
               <pb n="10" facs="tcp:33757:7"/>
               <p>All which Penalties and Forfeitures (one half to Their Majeſties, their Heirs and
Succeſſors, for the Support of the Government, the other Moi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty to the Informer that ſhall
Sue for the ſame) ſhall be recovered by Bill, Plaint or Information, in any Court of Record
within this Province where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in no Eſſoyn, Protection, Wager of Law, <hi>Non vult ulterius
Projequi</hi> or In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>junction ſhall be allow'd. Any thing in this Act or any other to the
con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trary thereof in any wife notwithſtanding. And all manner of Perſons are hereby Required,
to be aiding and aſſiſting to the Officer or Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cers, as ſhall be appointed to Collect
and Receive the Exciſe aforeſaid in the due Execution of their Reſpective Offices.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>And it is further Enacted by the Authority</hi> aforeſaid, That there be Commiſſioners
nominated, appointed and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioned by the Governour and Council, to Receive all Entries,
and to tranſact and manage all and whatſoever doth relare unto this Act, and the due
obſervance thereof; which Commiſſioners ſhall Appoint and Employ ſuch and ſo many
Officers under them, as they ſhall find needful for that purpoſe, the ſaid Commiſſioners,
and all other Officers to be Employed under them, before their Entring upon the Execution of their
reſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctive Offices, ſhall be Sworn before the Governour, or Lievtenant Gover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour, or one, or
more Members of the Council, or two Juſtices of the Peace, to deal truly and faithfully in the
Execution of the ſame; which aforeſaid Commiſſioners for their own Service and Labour in
this Affair, and the payment of all their Under Officers and Charges whatſoever ſhall be
allowed, one juſt ſixth part of all ſuch Moneys as ſhall be Collected and brought into the
Publick Treaſury, by vertue of this Act, the ſaid Commiſſioners to account with the
Treaſurer for all their Collections.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>And it is likewiſe further Enacted and De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clared by the Authority aforeſaid,</hi> That
every Ship or Veſſel above Twelve Tons coming into any Port or Ports of this Province, to Trade
or Traffick, the major part of the Owners whereof are not belonging to this Province, ſhall every
Voyage they make, pay twelve pence <hi>per</hi> Tun, or one pound of good and new Gunpowder for
each Tun. Such Ship or Veſſel is in Burthen, to be imployed for the Supply of Their Majeſties
Caſtles and Forts within this Province, to be received by the Treaſurer, or ſuch other, as in
the ſeveral Ports or Places ſhall be appointed to receive the ſanſe.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>And it is hereby Enacted and Declared by the Authority aforeſaid,</hi> That this preſent
Act, Entituled, An Act, <hi>For Impoſt, Exciſe; and Tonage of Shipping,</hi> ſhall remain and
continue in force for the term and ſpace of one whole year, and no longer: A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny thing herein
before contained to the contrary thereof in any wiſe not<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>withſtanding.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="naval office" type="Act">
               <pb n="11" facs="tcp:33757:7"/>
               <opener>
                  <dateline>Province of the MASSACH<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>SETS-BAY.</dateline>
               </opener>
               <head>An Act, For the Erecting of a Naval-Office.</head>
               <p>WHereas by Act of Parliament, made in the Fifteenth Year of King <hi>Charles</hi> the Second,
Entituled, <hi>An Act for the En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>couragement of Trade,</hi> It is Provided, That no Ship or
Veſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſel, coming to any Land, Iſland, Plantation, Colony, or Territory, or Place, to His
Majeſty or Heirs and Succeſſors belonging in <hi>America,</hi> ſhall Lade or Unlade any
Goods or Commodities whatſoever, un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>til the Maſter or Commander of ſuch Ship or Veſſel,
ſhall firſt have made known to the Governour of ſuch Land, Iſland, Plantation, Colony
Terri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tory or Place, or ſuch other Perſon or Officer, as ſhall be by him thereunto Authorized
and Appointed, the Arrival of the ſaid Ship or Veſſel, with her Name, and the Name and
Surname of her Maſter or Commander, and have ſhewn to him, that ſhe is an
<hi>Engliſh-built</hi> Ship, or made good, by producing Certificate, that ſhe is a Ship or
Veſſel free, and Navigated with an <hi>Engliſh</hi> Maſter, and three fourth parts of the
Mari<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners <hi>Engliſh</hi> Men, under the pain of the Loſs of Ship or Veſſel and Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>parel.
Now for the due and more effectual obſervation of ſaid Act of Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, and that all undue
Trading contrary to the ſaid Act may be pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vented in this Their Majeſties Province of the
Maſſachuſets-Bay.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Be it Enacted and Ordained by the Gover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour, Council and Repreſentatives in General
Aſſembly Convened.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <hi>And it it is hereby Enacted and Ordained by the Authority of the ſame.</hi> That in the
ſeveral Ports and Places hereafter mentioned, there ſhall be a Naval Office Erected, wherein
the Officers by the Governour to be appointed, for the ends aforeſaid, ſhall duely attend: That
is to ſay, At <hi>Boſton,</hi> for the Port of <hi>Boſton</hi> and <hi>Charlstown;</hi> at
<hi>Salem,</hi> for the Port of <hi>Salem</hi> and <hi>Marble-head;</hi> at <hi>Ipſwich,</hi> at
<hi>Newbury,</hi> at <hi>Ki<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>ery,</hi> at
<hi>Plimouth,</hi> and at <hi>Briſtol:</hi> At which Naval-Office, all Maſters of Ships or
Veſſels arriving in this Province, ſhall make their Entry with the Officer, according as the
ſaid Act of Parliament requires.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>And be it alſo Enacted by the Authority</hi> aforeſaid, That all Maſters of Ships or
Veſſels, Sailing out of this Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vince, ſhall before their Sailing out thereof, Clear their
ſaid Ships or Veſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſels in the ſaid Naval-Office. And that an Officer be appointed at
<hi>Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tha's Vineyard,</hi> and another at <hi>Nantucket,</hi> to Enter and Clear all Veſſels
paſſing to and from thence, but not to be accounted Ports, for the Unli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very or Lading of any
of the Enumerated Commodities. And the Fees in the ſaid Office to be demanded and received,
ſhall be theſe following, and no other, <hi>viz.</hi>
               </p>
               <pb n="12" facs="tcp:33757:8"/>
               <p>
                  <table>
                     <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell role="label">P.</cell>
                        <cell role="label">Sh.</cell>
                        <cell role="label">P.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>For Entring and Clearing all Ships and Veſſels Trading to this place from Abroad
(excepting, <hi>Connecticut, Rhode-I<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſland, Narraganſet,</hi> and <hi>New-Hampſhire</hi>)
<hi>viz.</hi> Two Shillings Entring, and Two Shilling Clearing.</cell>
                        <cell>00</cell>
                        <cell>4</cell>
                        <cell>00</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>Examining and Recording Certificates that Bonds are given acording to the Act of Navigation,
Two Shillings.</cell>
                        <cell>00</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>00</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>A Bond given according to the Act of Navigation, and for the Copying of the ſame, to be
Tranſmitted for <hi>England.</hi> Three Shillings.</cell>
                        <cell>00</cell>
                        <cell>3</cell>
                        <cell>00</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>A Certificate of the Lading. Two Shillings.</cell>
                        <cell>00</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>00</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>For Entring and Clearing all Veſſels Trading to and from <hi>Connecticut, Rhode-Iſland,
Narraganſet,</hi> and <hi>New-Hamp<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhioe,</hi> Five Shillings <hi>per</hi> Year, or
Twelve-pence each Voy age, at the Maſters Choice.</cell>
                        <cell>00</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>00</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>A Certificate for Veſſels Lading of Goods, carried in them from Port to Port, within the
Province. One Shilling</cell>
                        <cell>00</cell>
                        <cell>1</cell>
                        <cell>00</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>A Certificate for Goods of the Growth of <hi>Europe,</hi> carried out of the Province, to
other Plantations. Two Shillings.</cell>
                        <cell>00</cell>
                        <cell>2</cell>
                        <cell>00</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>For every Oath Adminiſtred. Six-pence.</cell>
                        <cell>00</cell>
                        <cell>00</cell>
                        <cell>6</cell>
                     </row>
                  </table>
               </p>
               <p>And the ſaid Naval Officer is hereby Impowred to Adminiſter the Oaths, required by ſaid
Act of Parliament.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="bills of credit" type="Act">
               <opener>
                  <dateline>Province of the <hi>Maſſachuſets-Bay.</hi>
                  </dateline>
               </opener>
               <head>An Act, For Making the Former Bills of Cre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dit, to Paſs Currant, in Future
Pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments.</head>
               <p>WHereas Their Majeſties Affairs within this <hi>Province,</hi> do re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quire a ſpeedy advance
for the Defence of the <hi>Province,</hi> and the Proſecution of the <hi>War,</hi> againſt
<hi>Their French</hi> and <hi>Indian</hi> Enemies, and there being no Stock at preſent in the
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:33757:8"/>Treaſury to ſupply the ſame, or to defray other the Neceſſary Charges
for Support of the Government.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Be it therefore Ordained, and Enacted</hi> By the Governour, Council and Repreſentatives,
Convened in Ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neral Aſſembly. <hi>And it is Enacted, by the Autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity of the ſame,</hi>
That all Bills of Public Credit iſſued forth, by Order of the <hi>General Court</hi> of the
late <hi>Colony</hi> of the <hi>Maſſachuſets-Bay,</hi> ſhall paſs Currant within this
<hi>Province,</hi> in all Payments Equivalent to Money, for the ſum in each Bill reſpectively
mentioned (excepting all Specialties and Contracts made before Publication hereof;) and in all
Publick payments, at Five <hi>Per Cent,</hi> advance. And for Encouragement to ſuch Perſon or
Perſons, as are Poſſeſſors of ſaid Bills, to lend them for the Service of the Publick.
It is further <hi>Enacted, by the Authority aforeſaid,</hi> That they and every of them, who
ſhall ſo do, be ſecured by the Publick Taxes and other Revenues, ariſing within this
<hi>Province</hi> already Granted, and ſhall be reimburſt and paid in money within the ſpace
of Twelve Moneths, out of the ſaid Taxes and Revenues, ſuch ſum and ſumms, as he or they
ſhall Reſpectively ſo lend, and deliver unto the Treaſurer of this Their Majeſties
Province, in Bills as aforeſaid, to be made to appear by Receipt. Provided that ſuch of ſaid
Bills, and no other, as ſhall be Indorſed by Capt. <hi>Jeremiah Dummer,</hi> and Mr.
<hi>Francis Burroughs,</hi> ſhall be accounted Currant, Excepting for payment of thoſe Rates,
that were Grant<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed before the Arrival of His Excellency the Govenour. And the ſaid Capt.
<hi>Jeremiah Dummer,</hi> and Mr. <hi>Francis Burroughs,</hi> are hereby appointed to Receive in
all Bills which any Perſon or Perſons ſhall lend as aforeſaid, and deliver the ſame to
the Treaſurer.</p>
               <p>Provided alſo, that all Perſons, who ſhall lend their Bills, as aforeſaid, ſhall have
Credit for all Summs, which they ſhall have to pay in all publick payments whatſoever; being
<hi>Bona Fide,</hi> for their own account, to be allowed them by diſcount, upon a Note from the
Treaſurer.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="transporting militia" type="Act">
               <pb n="14" facs="tcp:33757:9"/>
               <opener>
                  <dateline>Province of the <hi>Maſſachuſets-Bay.</hi>
                  </dateline>
               </opener>
               <head>An Act, For Tranſporting of part of the Militia, of the Province, Or Obliging Them to March
to the Relief of the Neigh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bouring Provinces, or Colonies.</head>
               <p>FOrasmuch as in this time of War, there may be Occaſion for the Raiſing of Soul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>diers, and
Tranſporting or Marching of them out of the Limits of this Province, into the Neighbouring
Provinces and Colonies of <hi>New Hampſhire, Rhode Iſland. Connecticut, Narraganſett,</hi> or
<hi>New York,</hi> for the proſecuti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of the <hi>French</hi> or <hi>Indian</hi> Enemy, and the
Defence of Their Majeſties Subjects, and In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>treſts. <hi>Be it Enacted and Ordained by the
Governour Council and Repreſentatives, Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vened in General Court. And it is Enacted By the
Authority of the ſame,</hi> That in the Vacancy of the General Aſſembly, it ſhall be in the
Liberty of His Excellency the preſent Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernour, by and with the advice and conſent of the
Council, to Raiſe, and Tranſport, ſuch part of the Militia of this Province, as they ſhall
find needful, or Oblige them to March into any of the before-named Provinces or Colonies, for
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:33757:9"/>the ends aforeſaid, at any Time or Times, with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in the Space of Six months
next, and at no time afterward, without their Free and Voluntary conſent, or the conſent of the
Great and Gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral Court or Aſſembly; any thing in this pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent Act, contained to the
contrary thereof, in any wiſe notwithſtanding.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="courts of justice" type="Act">
               <opener>
                  <dateline>Province of the <hi>Maſſachuſetts-Bay.</hi>
                  </dateline>
               </opener>
               <head>An Act, For the Holding of Courts of Juſtice.</head>
               <p>FOrasmuch as the orderly Regulation, and Well-Eſtabliſhment of Courts of Juſtice is of
great Concernment. And the Publick Occaſions with reference to the War, and otherwiſe being
ſo Preſſing at this Seaſon, that this Court cannot now conveniently Sit longer to Adviſe
upon, and fully Settle the ſame. But to the Intent that Juſtice be not Obſtructed, or
Delayed.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Be it Ordained and Enacted by the Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernour, Council and Repreſentatives, Conve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned in
General Aſſembly, and it is Ordained by the Authority of the ſame.</hi> That on or before the
laſt <hi>Tueſday</hi> of <hi>July next,</hi> there be a General Seſſions of the Peace, Held
and Kept in each Reſpective County within this Province, by the Juſtices of the ſame County,
or three of them at the leaſt, (the firſt Juſtice of the <hi>Quorum</hi> then preſent to
Preſide) who are hereby Impowred to Hear and Determine all Matters Relating to the Conſervation
of the Peace, and whatſoever is by them Cognizable according to Law. And to Grant Licenſes to
ſuch Perſons within the ſame County, being firſt approved of
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:33757:10"/>by the Select-Men of each Town, where ſuch Perſons Dwell, whom they ſhall
think fit, to be Employed as Inholders, or Retailers of Wines, or ſtrong Liquors. And that a
Seſſions of the Peace be ſucceſſively Held and Kept as aforeſaid, within the ſeveral
Counties at the ſame times, and places, as the County Courts, or Inferior Courts of Common Pleas,
are herein after ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed to be Kept.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>And it is further Enacted by the Authority</hi> aforeſaid, That the County Courts, or
Inferior Courts of Common-Pleas, be Held and Kept in each Reſpective County, by the Juſtices of
the ſame County, or three of them at the leaſt, (the firſt Juſtice of the <hi>Quorum</hi>
then preſent to Preſide) at the ſame times and Places they have been formerly Kept according
to Law, for the Hearing and Determining of all Civil Acti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons ariſing or happening within the
ſame, Triable at the Common Law, according to former Uſage. The Juſtices for Holding and
Keeping of the ſaid Court within the County of <hi>Suffolk,</hi> to be particularly appointed and
Commiſſioned by the Governour, with the Advice and Conſent of the Council. And that all
Writts, or Attachments ſhall Iſſue out of the Clerks Office of the ſaid ſeveral Courts.
Signed by the Clerk of ſuch Court, di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rected unto the Sheriff of the County, his Under-Sheriff,
or Deputy: The Jurors to Serve at ſaid Courts, to be Choſen according to former Cuſtome, by
and of the Freeholders, and other Inhabitants, qualified as is directed in Their Majeſties Royal
Charter.</p>
               <p>This Act to Continue untill other proviſion be made by the GENERAL COURT or ASSEMBLY.</p>
            </div>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:33757:10"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
